Guide to the Charles H. S. Davis Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles H. S. Davis papers
1855-1920
MS 1152
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
Correspondence, writings, and genealogical materials relating to the Davis and Harris families. The correspondence and writings reflect Davis' avocational activities as editor of Biblia, a journal of Oriental archeology, his interest in local Connecticut history, and his research into his wife's and his own family history.
Davis, Charles Henry Stanley, 1840-1917
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Emily H. Hall, 1948.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence and other papers of Charles H.S. Davis and his wife, Caroline E. (Harris) Davis, much of it undated. The first half of the collection contains a small number of incoming letters dealing in the main with Davis' writings and with publications which he edited, and a larger number of writings by Davis. These include a notebook, short essays and speeches, and one longer manuscript. Several of the writings deal with political matters; others discuss medicine and ancient history. There are, in addition, essays written by others and sent to Davis for publication in Biblia.
The second half of the collection, except for one letter from Caroline to Charles (1872 Jun 17), is devoted to the history of the Davis and Harris families and consists in part of materials relating to The Davis Family Record, a monthly journal edited by Davis in 1867 and 1868. Included are letters addressed to both Charles and Caroline, six notebooks concerned mostly with the Harris family, loose notes, and printed material.
These papers were donated to Yale University in 1948 by Emily H. Hall.
Biographical / Historical
Charles H. S. Davis was a physician. He was a resident of Meriden, Connecticut, a member of the Connecticut legislature (1873, 1885, 1886), the author of numerous books on medicine and Oriental studies, and the editor of Biblia from 1887-.
Archaeology; Connecticut -- History; Davis, Charles Henry Stanley, 1840-1917; Davis family; Harris family
- Inventory
  - General correspondence, 1877-1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Writings
    - Notebook, [ca. 1855-65] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Essays and Speeches, [1884?]-1912, undated (Box 1, Folder 3 - 5)
    - "The Human Machine" (Ms and typed copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - "List of Subscribers to Index"; Printed announcement for A History of the Town of Wallingford, Conn., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts by others submitted to Biblia, undated (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Davis, Caroline Elizabeth (Harris): ALS to Charles H.S. Davis, 1872 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Davis and Harris family history
    - Correspondence, 1867-1904, undated (Box 2, Folder 12 - 18)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 2, Folder 19 - 22)
    - Loose notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 23 - 25)
    - Printed matter, [ca. 1870-1915] (Box 2, Folder 26)